SERGEI SOLOD

solodsergey287@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/sergeisolod https://sergeisolod.github.io

SUMMARY

Experienced Middle Frontend developer (4 and a half years full time) with deep understanding of developing complex projects in product startups (Scrum methodology). I've developed about 20 commercial projects (SEO frendly) from idea to release, which are used by thousands of people, remade many projects from legacy technologies to new ones. Expert level of JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, CSS and other technologies.

Skills

Technical: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, CSS3, HTML5, Saas, Jest, NextJS, VueJS, Webpack, Babel.js, Gulp, REST APIs, WebSocket, ESLint, MaterialUI, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, Git, Terminal macOS/Linux.

Other: Jira, Figma, Zeplin, Scrum, Agile, SEO, UI, UX, Wordpress, Joomla, Wix, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager.

Experience

Digift Gift Cards

Remote (Thessaloniki, Greece)

Middle Frontend Developer Feb 2020 - Present (3 years 5 months)

- I've developed about 20 complex projects (admin panels, stores, widgets, payment systems, etc.) from idea to production. I've developed this in a large team using the Scrum methodology. These projects are used by tens of thousands of people, they bring my company hundreds of thousands of dollars.
- I've remade 5 large old projects from legacy technologies (PHP 5, Vue 1, jQuery) to new ones (TypeScript, React, Redux). This significantly reduced the time to implement features in these projects, saving thousands of hours of development.
- I supported all projects, including legacy code, I fixed bugs, implemented features, improved existing projects, regularly reviewed code. This allowed my company to increase sales and improve its reputation.
- I was fully responsible for most of the projects of my company. I participated in the architectural development of the projects. Many fundamental decisions were made by me, such as the choice of technologies, programming language, architecture. This allowed my company to use the latest technology and best practice.
- I trained and mentored the employees and also made training videos for colleagues, clients and developers. Thanks to this, new employees quickly began to bring profit to the company.
- I've done SEO optimization of our projects on React (Next, Node), developed email letters, WebSocket payment processor, SPA with authorization and token, complex animations with json, images. This allowed my company to appear more often in Google search results and present a quality product to users.

Foodle

On-site (St Petersburg City, Russia) Feb 2019 - Jan 2020 (1 year)

Junior Frontend Developer

- I've developed a project (React, Redux) that helps to see restaurant menus and order food. This is the main project of my company, which allowed the company to increase revenue and occupy the market.
- Together with the development team and team leader, I participated in the development of the future project
 architecture. I suggested ideas that were implemented and reduced the load on the server, increased the
 productivity of the project.
- I've fixed the bugs of the company's projects, implemented a lot of features. It improved my company's reputation and increased the number of clients.

Freelance

Remote (St Petersburg City, Russia)

May 2018 - Jan 2019 (9 months)

Frontend Developer

- I've developed many websites for my clients, which allowed them to be represented on the Internet, sell services, increase revenue and sales, improve reputation.
- I supported my clients' sites, fixed errors and bugs, introduced new features, I also supported the CMS platforms WordPress, Wix, Joomla. This increased the sales, improved the attitude of users towards the product.
- I implemented in the site code GA, GTM and client required libraries. This allowed my clients to see statistics, work comfortably, find their weaknesses and increase sales.

Educational

Saint Petersburg State University

Bachelor's degree (Sep 2016 - Jun 2020)